

# MOHAMMED RISHAD V K

Senior Software Engineer (Python, Django, Flask, Postgres, RestAPI, AWS, Docker)

More than 5 years of experience working with Scalable, Reusable, Reliable, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) in Software Development. I'm a quick learner and highly flexible to adapt to new challenges, take ownership, handle multiple responsibilities and mentoring.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Backend Developer, StudySmarter GmbH

MUNICH, GERMANY (REMOTE FROM INDIA)

Dec 2021 - Present

- Taking ownership for the development and maintaining different learning modes like Practice, Quiz, Spaced Repetition, Type to answer, etc.
- Improvising and adding new feature to core product like Flashcards,
  Documents, Summary, Textbook, Exercises, etc.
- Collaborating with team and cross functional team to achieve common goals.
- Writing unittest, integration, functional, etc to make sure quality of the product.
- Peer code review with cross functional teams.
- Technologies
  - Python, Django, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, CloudFront, Sentry, CloudWatch, EC2, EKS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

# Senior Software Engineer, Reckonsys Tech Labs Pvt. Ltd

BENGALURU, KARNATAKA, INDIA

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the business to implement features and understand use cases (US, Europe, India).
- Contribute to design and development of Backend and API's using Monolith and Microservice Architecture.
- Contribute to the technical design and development APIs with performance and scalability in mind.
- Research, suggest and implement new solutions in performance of backend service.
- Integration of third-party API's and creating webhooks for the business.
- Experience with devops and infrastructure practices and technology like CI, deployment automation, provisioning, Amazon AWS.
- Mentoring and training new joinees and juniors.
- Some industries worked are Hotel, Sports, Hiring, Transport, Aviation, Healthcare, Analytics, Travel, etc.
- Technologies

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS,
 GraphQL, RestAPI, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Elixir / Phoenix,

Malappuram, Kerala India, 676510 +91(0)9567802281 mohammedrishad.vk@gmail.com

#### LINKS

- Website
- LinkedIn
- Github
- StackOverflow

### **SKILLS**

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, GraphQL, RestAPI, CSS,, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Git, AWS, GCP, PyTest, Unittest, Linux(Ubuntu), Unix, Jira, Agile

#### Familiar:

Kubernetes, SQLAlchemy, Elixir, Phoenix, Node.js, Express JS, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, XML, JSON, Elastic Search, Numpy, Pandas, Mac OS, Windows, Terraform, Kafka, Data Structures, Algorithms

# **AWARDS & HONORS**

**SayOne Rockstar** – Best Performer (Dec 2018).

Winner Djangothon2018 by HackerEarth (1st Prize Winner).

**Acknowledged** by Google, Microsoft, Sony, Freelancer, Kaspersky, eBay, CRIS, etc. for reporting security bugs.

### **LANGUAGES**

- English (Proficient, C1)
- German (Beginner, A1)
- Malayalam (Native, C2)

Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, SES, CloudFront, IAM, Lambda, EC2, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

#### Clients

 NuFlights, ClipHire, Pharmallama, TransportSimple,, Acumen Aviation, Kiplist, D8aDriven, Moonllight, Vigna World

# Software Engineer, SayOne Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2018 - May 2019

- Help to develop 5+ web applications from scratch.
- Managed team of 4 members including Backend and Frontend Developers.
- Developed a highly scalable ecommerce SaaS platform for independent pet retailers with Django and Postgres. (Worked on DB Design, Dashboard(Role, Orders, Invoicing, Products, Theming, Coupon, Offers) and Frontend Pages, etc)
- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the client to implement features and understand use cases.
- Developed and maintained an article website for big data, blockchain, and artificial intelligence having insights and jobs..

#### Technologies

Python / Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 TypeScript, Angular, Celery, Redis, Elastic Search, RestAPI, Git,
 SendGrid, Kafka

#### Clients

o <u>eTailPet</u>, <u>FeedMyFurBaby</u>, <u>Datafloq</u>, <u>Mavin</u>, <u>BeCo</u>, <u>ProteinForPets</u>,

# Python Developer, CogniCor Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

- Involved in the development and maintaining of Chatbot and Dashboard using Python 2.7, Django 1.8, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MongoDB.
- Build Analytics Dashboard to help the clients to analyze/visualize chats and leads.
- Created periodic bank account statements for Federal Bank.
- Closely worked with banks and Insurance companies to collect chatbot requirements.

### Technologies

o Python, Django, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Git

#### Clients

o ICICI Bank, OCBC Bank, Federal Bank, Tata Capital, Atos.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Calicut — M.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2014 - 2016

- Blue Card Eligible EU / German
- Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 7.13/10 (71.3%) A grade

### University of Calicut — B.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2011 - 2014

Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 2.76/4 (69 %) - B grade

### **INTERESTS**

- Open Source Contribution
- Competitive Programming
- Web Security Research
- Mentoring
- Continuous Learning
- Photography
- Travel
- Football (Soccer)